After we have learned about the Ford Focus and algorithm in animation, and we have to get deeply into
the Ford Focus, and now let's go to C compiler and please guys write these codes down in order to save
them for later review for the exam and the interview.
So we start by including the studio and defining these variables into an entire capacity.
The flow, color and spread.
These are their areas, and this is.
To the IRA, this is also to the IRA, the capacity in the flow, to the IRA and the color is here and
the bread is as an IRA.
So we start by creating an inert variable into the method called men of returning type is end.
And it took parameter two variables in X and into Y.
We start comparing if x less than Y, then return X.
Otherwise, it will return y return the biggest.
The smallest, OK.
No.
We create also had and pain, and we start by making here that new method called in.
You remember the interview and deck?
These are for the queue.
So here in the four Fulkerson, we are going to use something like queue.
So and like the methods of the queue, the NQ and the deck in queue will add at the tail equal to X
Ink X.
So we are going to add at the tail, the queue and tail + + and color at Index X equal to be if we are
going to remove.
Data are going to use that fact method.
So we start by creating an index equal to you at index had and had increased it by one and then assigned
the Color Index X equipped to see and return x.
So this is for the first one for the by dealing with that Q.
No.
Using the BFC as a searching algorithm.
OK.
So the breadth first search as a searching algorithm.
Please go back to the BFC in the previous videos to learn about the breadth first search if you missed
it.
So we took in the perimeter meter to start and the target.
And we assign you envy, and we make a for loop for you equals here and ula's then and you plus plus
the sequence and color at index you equal to so had equal to tail equal to zero.
Now, ink, you start here.
We have added a start and prayed at the start equal minus one.
Here is the binary search concept, while had does not equal to tail.
So we are moving the cursors.
Start, Dick, like you equal Dick.
OK, so we have removed Dec now for the equal to zero Vilas then and V Plus plus we are going.
To check if this condition and this condition is true here and here is true, then ink you VE and it
at index fee equal to you, then return color at Target Equal Equal to see.
So we have assigned valuable a and the Vardi will see no applying the Ford Focus on algorithm.
This is the concept of our algorithm by creating a method that returns.
The return type is integer and took into parameters the insource and in sync.
We start I.J and you and inthe max flow equal to zero.
We start since we have to the arrays, so we are going to make a and you make use of nested editing
nested loops or.
Four are equal to zero, and J, what the zero, so we are going to loop through all the AI and through
all the G for less and jaitley's then and assign every time here flow at index are equal and index equal
to zero.
So we are zeroing and enclosing this array to zero.
The flow now updating the residual values of edges while belman and by the y la by a breadth first search.
With this, the method that we have created, we passed the source and the sink.
So and increment equal to zero for the increment.
This is for the increment
increment equal to minimum.
And we passed the increment and capacity and this and it may be confusing, and it's very hard case
because it's consist of many calculations, so I need from you to write them down and solve them and
add to it to like, understand them very well and to practice fairly good practice about these algorithms.
Now we use a for loop, another full loop start from and minus one for at index you greater than or
equal to zero and you equal to that index.
You know, we start by flow, increased flow by flow that all the flow plus increment and then we reverse
the indices.
So you.
Here comes at Index I.
It was at Index J becomes at the index and the max flow equals the old maximum flow plus increment and
we return to maximum flow.
OK.
In order to test our program, we start by creating a foreign invested for a loop because we have the
capacity to do that.
We initialize them to zero.
This is the first step.
Putting all the elements at this matrix is equal to zero.
OK, so.
And equal to sex and equal to seven.
We start by capacity at index zero one is eight zero four three and so index equal to zero and equal
to five.
Now we need to print maximum flow, which is the maximum flow of the Ford Focus on records and how to
find the path between these points and how, which is that this capacity with with corresponding capacity.
So these are the capacity between the two edges.
We apply the Ford Focus, an algorithm we pass as equal to zero and to equal to five.
OK.
So for this, we have created the Ford Focus algorithm and C, and this is tested in all compilers of
C.
And I want from you to write this down and try to make it.
And like any copybook or API files that you can review and revise before that into.